ILGWU Master Agreements, Out-of-Business Contracts 5780/146
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Master Agreements Out-of-Business Contracts
1941-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/146
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection consists of agreements and contracts between the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union and defunct garment manufacturing firms.
5510669
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, August 10, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/075: ILGWU Collective Bargaining Agreements 5780/075 mf: ILGWU Collective Bargaining Agreements on Microfilm 5780/085: ILGWU National War Labor Board case files 5780/145: ILGWU Association Agreements, Out-of-Business Contracts 5780/147: ILGWU Independents, Out-of-Business Contracts 5780/158: ILGWU Out-of-Business Contracts 5780/191: ILGWU Association Contracts 5780/202: ILGWU Operations Department Collective Bargaining Agreements
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States
5510669
- Associated Sportswear Companies, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Barbizon Corporation, 1962-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Berkshire Apparel, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bobbie Brooks, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Country Miss, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Country Miss, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Country Miss, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Country Miss, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Country Miss, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Country Miss, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Jonathan Logan, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Jonathan Logan, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Jonathan Logan, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Jonathan Logan, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Jonathan Logan, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Jonathan Logan, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Jonathan Logan, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Kenrose Manufacturing, 1956-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Majestic Specialties, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Mode O'Day, 1941-1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Mode O'Day, 1951-1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Mode O'Day, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Mode O'Day, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Mode O'Day, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Mode O'Day, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Mode O'Day, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Puritan Fashions, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Puritan Fashions, 1973-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- United Merchants and Manufacturing, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Wentworth Manufacturing, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)